The RL-10 rocket engine,
RL-10火箭引擎
power plant for Centaur and Saturn, is the result of years of development.
半人马上面级和土星火箭系列的动力装置 是多年研发的成果
The highest performance engine built in the free world uses safe, reliable, and dependable hydrogen.
是自由世界(冷战时期西方的统称)建造的最高性能引擎 使用安全可靠的液氢
To maintain the high degree of reliability of the RL-10, vital parts are assembled under stringent laboratory conditions.
为了维持RL-10的高可靠性 重要部件需要在严格的实验室环境中装配
Following a typical engine through its paces, the thrust chamber tubes are installed.
推力室管束安装 按照典型的引擎装配流程
After the assembly is placed over a mandrel the manifolds and bands can be attached.
将装配体放在心轴上后，就可以将歧管和加强带安装上去。
Silver wire is laid in for furnace brazing.
用于炉中钎焊的银焊丝被铺设
Placed in a retort, the chamber is readied for the furnace.
推力室被放在一个蒸馏器中 做好了进炉的准备
Once braised the chamber undergoes testing to assure trouble-free operation.
一旦在炉中焖好 推力室会进行测试以确保无故障运行
Liquid nitrogen is forced through the chamber to perform thermal shock tests.
液氮被打入推力室进行温度冲击试验
Pressurized with gaseous nitrogen the chamber is checked for leaks.
用氮气进行加压 检查推力室是否有泄漏
The inspected sub-assembly is dried out in a special oven.
检验过的子组件在特殊的烘箱中烘干
Final chamber assembly is completed with the installation of the injector.
喷注器安装完成后，推力室组装完成
A special jig is lowered to accurately align the injector.
为了准确地对齐喷注器 特制的夹具被降下来
Then the chamber goes for final machining prior to assembly of the complete engine.
然后在组装完整的发动机之前 推力室进行最终加工
On the Assembly floor all parts come together fuel lines.
在装配楼层 所有的来到这里 燃料管线
Valves turbo pumps are brought from clean rooms assembled installed and inspected.
阀门 涡轮增压泵从无尘室运来 组装 安装然后检查
Multiple inspections of each component and sub assembly assures maximum reliability.
对每个部件和子组件进行多次检查 确保最大的可靠性
Ready for action the completed engine must undergo the test of firing.
准备运行前 完成的引擎必须经过点火测试
The RL-10 is made ready for transport to the test site.
RL-10已经做好准备 可以运往试验场
The operating principle of the RL-10 can best be shown by this simple diagram.
这个简单的图能很好地说明RL-10的工作原理
Hydrogen at 37 degrees rankine minus 423 degrees Fahrenheit enters through the inlet shutoff valve.
液氢在37兰氏度 423华氏度 (-252.2℃) 时从进给截断阀进入
Passes through the first stage pump into the second stage pump
通过第一级泵进入第二级泵
where it is discharged at 1,000 pounds per square inch.
以每平方英寸1,000磅 (6.9MPa) 的压强排出
Then it passes through the cooling jacket manifold through half of the tubes.
然后它通过冷却歧管套 再通过束管的一半
Through the turnaround manifold back through the long tubes to the exit manifold
经过转弯歧管 反回到长束管 来到出口歧管
and through the venturi into the turbine.
然后通过文氏管进入涡轮
At this point, the hydrogen is now gas at 850 pounds per square inch
此时氢气已是每平方英寸850磅 (5.9MPa) 的气体了
and 350 degrees Rankine - 110 degrees Fahrenheit
温度在350兰氏度 - 110华氏度 (43.3℃)
and provides the power to drive the hydrogen and oxygen pumps.
提供驱动氢泵和氧泵的动力
It then goes through the main shutoff valve into the injector and to the combustion chamber.
然后它通过主截断阀进入喷注器再进到燃烧室
Drawn in through the single stage oxygen pump oxygen flows through the inlet valve.
液氧通过单级氧泵流入进给阀
Directly through the mixture ratio control valve into the injector to combine with the hydrogen in the chamber.
直接通过混合比调节阀进入喷注器 与燃烧室内的氢气结合
The engine itself is as simple as the diagram to demonstrate
发动机本身就像图表那样简单 展示
hydrogen enters at this point flows through the first stage pump into the second stage pump
液氢在此处通过第一级泵流向第二级泵
passes through the cooling jacket manifold down through half the tubes to the turnaround manifold up the long tubes
通过冷却歧管套 往下过束管的一半 经过转弯歧管 往上到长束管
collected at the exit manifold
集于出口歧管
through the venturi into the turbine.
经过文氏管进入涡轮
There it provides the power to drive the hydrogen and oxygen pumps.
在那里它提供驱动氢泵和氧泵的动力
Then around the large line through the main fuel shutoff valve into the injector and then to the combustion chamber.
然后绕过大管路 通过主燃料截断阀进入喷注器 再到燃烧室
On the oxygen side,
液氧这边
oxygen flows through the inlet valve through a single stage pump
液氧通过单级氧泵流入进给阀
directly through the mixture ratio control valve into the injector
直接通过混合比调节阀进入喷注器
Arriving at one of the vertical test stands, the RL-10 is installed and made ready for test firing.
到达其中一个垂直测试台 RL-10被安装好 准备进行试点火
Spaced firing conditions will be simulated.
会模拟太空点火环境
A steam injector system lowers the pressure to the near vacuum of space.
蒸汽喷射系统将压力降低到接近宇宙的真空
On completion of this test firing,
在完成这项试点火后
the engine will be returned to the manufacturing area for complete disassembly inspection and reassembly.
发动机将被送回制造区进行完整的拆卸检查和重新组装
Years of experience, research and development
多年来 普惠公司
have gone into the design and manufacture of the Pratt & Whitney aircraft RL-10 rocket engines.
在设计和制造RL-10火箭引擎的过程中积累了丰富的经验和研发成果
The RL-10 is also undergone space condition testing at the NASA Lewis Research Center
RL-10还在NASA刘易斯研究中心进行了太空环境测试
where special viewing ports permit continual visual check of space condition firing.
那里的特殊观察口允许对太空环境点火进行持续的目视检查
Pratt & Whitney Aircraft's around-the-clock development program is helping accelerate the United States space efforts.
普惠公司的全天候研发项目正帮助加快美国的航天工作